[{"question":"Is  it  possible  to  separate  professional  ethics  from  personal  ethics","choices":[" no"," yes"," possible to some extent"," none of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Do you agree that Personal Ethics is the foundation of Professional Ethics","choices":[" yes to some extent"," Yes and No"," No"," Yes"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"What does the Professional Ethics deal","choices":[" It deals with the ethical standards accepted by the professional community"," It deals with the legal standards"," It deals with the business aspects"," It deals with official matters"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"What standards on which the Engineer have to comply with","choices":[" Legal"," Commerce"," The standards according to model rules of professional Conduct provided by various agencies , to the public , to the clients, to the employers and the customers","Ethical"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Expand the abbreviated word �NSPE�","choices":["National Scheme for professional Ethics"," National society for professional Engineers"," National sector~wise programme efficiency"," None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What are the codes provided by NSPE to apply in particular circumstances","choices":[" to avoid conflict of interest","  to understand the problem of engineers"," to protect wealth"," to inspect the agenda"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The following are the aims of the professional Ethics","choices":[" developing analytical  standards"," toleration on agreement and ambiguity"," sense of developing ethical principles"," recognition of ethical issues"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Are Engineers morally responsible for causing harm intentionally, negligently, or recklessly","choices":[" No"," Yes "," Yes to some extent"," None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What is one of  the three basic attitudes towards the responsibilities of Engineer","choices":[" minimalist","  uncritical acceptance of authority"," inspection"," none of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The responsibility of engineers are divided into ","choices":[" Four"," Three"," Two"," Five"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"What do you mean by �minimalist approach�","choices":["Sticking on maximum acceptable standards"," Sticking on to minimum acceptable standards"," Sticking on full acceptable standards"," None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What is emphasized in reasonable/considerable care","choices":[" Attention to those who are at risk of being harmed and to prevent the progress or adverse effect of harm"," Attention to those who are not at risk"," Attention on both of the above"," None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Is considerable care beyond the minimalist approach","choices":[" No"," Yes"," No to some extent"," Yes to extent"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"In �Good Work Views�, focus is given on","choices":[" Concept of skilful work"," Concept of legal work"," Concept of logical work"," The concept of responsibility beyond the legal and moral duty"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Is �Self �Interest� impediment or hindrance to responsibilty ","choices":["No"," Yes"," Yes to some extent"," None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Is �Fear� impediment or hindrance to responsibility ","choices":[" No"," yes to some extent"," Yes & No"," Yes"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"What is the other hindrance to the responsibility ","choices":[" self deception"," Self assessment"," Self realization"," Negligence"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Honesty is____________ ","choices":[" perfectness"," Readiness"," truthfulness","surrendering to God"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Dharma is__________ ","choices":[" Sincerity"," Castle belief"," What is good for the self","Truth of justice"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Honesty is __________ ","choices":[" Not liked by all"," Liked by all but not practiced"," liked in others"," liked by one and all"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Engineering honesty is doing ___________ ","choices":["What is right for oneself"," What is good for the society"," What is good for the employer"," What earns money quickly"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Engineers should not indulge in__________ ","choices":[" Fraudulent business "," constructive measures"," Healthy attitudes to words society"," None of above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Telling the truth when should not is ____________ ","choices":[" Honesty"," Dharma of an engineer"," Misusing the truth"," Business principle"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Misusing the truth is_______ ","choices":[" Disclosing the information when should not"," Sincerity in engineering"," Doing good service to the customer"," Upholding the dignity of the profession"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Failure to reveal the truth means__________ ","choices":[" Lying"," Protecting the employer in interest"," Protecting the company interest"," None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Deliberate deception means_____________ ","choices":[" An engineer is deliberately deceiving the customer"," An engineer is deceiving the employer"," An engineer is doing service to the society"," An engineer is doing good service to both employer and society"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Withholding information is ____________ ","choices":[" Omitting necessary information to customer"," Omitting necessary information to the employer"," Committing an offence"," committing an error of judgement"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Corrupting the truth means __________ ","choices":[" Conflicts of interest"," Conflicts of judgement"," Conflicts of service"," None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Integrity in engineering means____________ ","choices":[" Quality of being honest and fair"," Quality of service to the employer"," Quality of self~esteemed behaviour"," Quality of self~aggrandizement"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Integrity means ____________ ","choices":[" Not settling for less than what you deserve"," Not giving out anything at all"," Not yielding to public pressure"," Not sacrificing in approach and appearance"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Trimming in engineering means ____________ ","choices":[" Dressing the bushes"," Dressing hair"," Smoothing the irregularities to your convenience"," Smartness in approach and appearance"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Cooking in engineering means __________ ","choices":[" Cook the food"," Cook a story"," Retain only what you want","Leave out what others need"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Forging in engineering means ___________ ","choices":[" Shaping the metal"," Make a fraudulent copy"," Inventing some research data"," None of the above"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Plagiarism means ____________ ","choices":[" Use of intellectual property of others "," Copying wanted information from different sources"," Research work"," Knitting a theory to suit your arguments"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Trade secret doesn�t include _________ ","choices":[" Formulas"," Patterns"," Devices"," Colours"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Patent right is for _______ ","choices":[" 10 years"," 20 years"," 40 years"," 100 years"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Trademarks  doesn�t include ____________ ","choices":[" Designs"," Sounds"," Phrases"," Fair"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Copyright is for _____________ ","choices":[" 50 years after his or her death"," 15 years after his or her death"," 100 years after his or her death"," None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineer is not supposed to reveal any information to his client _____________ ","choices":[" In the interest of his client","In employer�s interest"," In the interest of the society"," None of the above"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Reliability in engineering means ____________ ","choices":[" Probability of a product or a system"," Quality of the person who sells the product"," Quality of the company which produces the product"," Probable use or misuse of a product"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Risk in engineering means __________ ","choices":[" Taking risk to venture out something "," Without taking risk nothing can be achieved"," The potential that something unwanted may occur"," An inadvertent oversight"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":" Liability means ____________ ","choices":["  Whenever an act harms others it must be compensated","  Compensation not obligatory","  When a customer buys a service or product liability ceases","  None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Risk as a maximizing benefit is understood by","choices":[" Risk /benefit analysis"," Straight �line benefit"," Cost/benefit analysis"," Break-analysis"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Conflicts of interest exists when an improper judgement is made by professional may not be due to","choices":["Protecting the public health","Temptations","Loyalties","Influences"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"It is not a kind of trademark","choices":["Goodwill","Symbols","Sounds","Designs"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Conflict of interest may be","choices":["Potential","False","Created","Imaginary"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Revealing confidential information means","choices":["Misusing the truth","Breach of contract","Criminal breach of trust","Violation of patent right"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The professional ethics deals with ________accepted by the professional group community","choices":["Ethical standards","Scientific standards","Moral standards","Social standards"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The obligation and prerogatives associated with a special role is referred to as","choices":["Role morality ","Duty","Responsibility"," Ethics"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The codes of ethics can be taken as guidelines by the engineers to","choices":["Resolve the conflicts","Formulate the problem","Overcome the work pressure ","Escape the responsibility"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"No code will give _____ to get solutions for ethical problems","choices":["An algorithm","Guidelines","Set of ideas","Ethical standards"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not taken as aim of engineer?","choices":["Shifting of responsibilities","Recognition of ethical issues","Moral imagination","Sense of responsibility"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Responsibility is assigned as belonging to persons in","choices":["Both (b) and (c) ","Rule","Morality","Obligation"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Recklessly causing harm is","choices":["Not with an intention to cause harm but acting in conscious awareness that harm is likely to take place","Unknowingly causing harm but failing to take due care ","Purposely causing harm","Both (a) and (b)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following doesn�t depict the attitude towards responsibility?","choices":["Protest","Good works","Reasonable care","Minimalist"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"In reasonable care concept of responsibility, the attention paid is to","choices":["Those who are at risk of being harmed","The employee","To client","Self"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineer tempted by their own interest to act in contrary to interest of others","choices":["Self~interest","Self~deception","Ignorance","Egoism"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Ignorance as a hurdle to responsibility is not due to","choices":["Fear","Over confidence","Lack of imagination"," pressure and deadlines"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The tendency of interpreting situations according to their views and imposing the views is","choices":["Egocentric","Self interest","Confined vision ","Both (b) and(c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineer COE emphasize that the engineer should have_____ in discharging their duties","choices":["Autonomy","Fidelity to employers","Obligation to public","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"________is not the symptom of group thinking","choices":["Egocentric tendency ","Mind guarding","Illusion of unanimity","Self~censorship"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Tendency of shifting responsibility will come down if there is","choices":["Group thinking","Microscopic vision","Fear","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not advised by the NSPE code to engineer?","choices":["Not to avoid deceptive acts","Not to use firms name in dishonest business","To have professional obligations","To be honest"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following qualities an responsible engineer should not have regard to risk?","choices":["Dishonest in assessing","Be aware of different approaches to the determination and risk","Not be deceiving","Aware of difficulty"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The owner of �Patent right� retains his patent right for ___________ years (OR)patent holder does not allow others to use patented information for ___________ years from date of filling","choices":["20","50","75","100"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The principle obligations of engineer is to safe guard the public by ","choices":["Spreading the information before the disaster occurs","Finding out the truth","Withholding the information","Deliberate deception"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the characteristics of high risk technologies susceptible to accident is complex","choices":["Combination ","working of system","Interaction","Designs"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the ways of reducing risk is","choices":["Tight coupling ","Complex interactions","Normalization of deviance","Changing the working systems"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"�Minimalist view� means","choices":["A concept of responsibility","A narrow thinking ","A ministerial view","A novel plan to minimize industrial loss"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Basic attitude towards responsibility is","choices":["Minimalist","Recklessly causing harm","Negligently causing harm","Intentionally causing harm"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"They are not trade secrets ","choices":["Principles","Patterns","Formulas","Devices"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not a trade secret?","choices":["Theorem","Equipment","Formulae","Pattern"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Formula of a soft drink is an example of","choices":["Trade secret","Patent","Copy right","Trade mark"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Copyright protects the expression of ideas but not the","choices":["Ideas themselves","Deriving ideas","Predicting ideas","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"A company cannot have claim if the knowledge used is","choices":["Generic information","Stolen from the company","Used to create the same product","Both (b) and (C)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not conflict of interest as applied to making judgement?","choices":["Virtual","Apparent","Potential","Actual"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"A fault tree is used to","choices":["Assess the risk involved","Claim compensation","Take free consent","Improve safety"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Risk estimation can be done by using","choices":["Event tree","Trimming","Cooking","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The use of intellectual property of others without their permission or credit is referred as","choices":["Plagiarism","Trimming","Cooking","Forging"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not preserved as an intellectual property?","choices":["Government regulations","Copyrights","Patents","Trade secrets"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Acceptable risk means ","choices":["Risk of harm equal to probability of producing benefits","Risk which is the natural part of the process","Inevitable risk","Risk which cannot be avoided"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Allowing increased number of deviances from prescribed standards of safety and acceptable risk is referred to as","choices":["Normalizing deviance","Identification of risk","Estimation of risk","Probable risk"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Lay public estimation of likely hood of low probability risks associated with the causes of life is generally","choices":["Over estimation","Under estimation","Actual estimation","Rough estimation"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"In which of the following the competent technical knowledge of engineers is not required for certification in cases involving?","choices":["Legal matters","Effective goods","Accidents","Patent violation"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Expert testimony doesn�t demand ","choices":["Adequate time for thorough investigation","Consulting extensively with lawyer","Expert legal knowledge","Objective and unbiased demeanour"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"In issuing testimony which of the following is not desired by an expert","choices":["Not to maintain an objective and be biased","Be open to information, even during the course of trial","Not to accept, if he cannot do so with good conscience","Not to accept, if there is no adequate time"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not the concept of responsibility?","choices":["Utilitarian","Minimalist","Reasonable care","Good works"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"For an ethical engineer responsibility is","choices":["Both legal and moral","Moral responsibility","Legal responsibility","Social responsibility"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One�s wish of being an ethical engineer ","choices":["His wish of being an ethical person","His family members wish of him being an ethical person","His employers wish of him being an ethical person","All of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"What is morally wrong?","choices":["Cannot be measured as constitutional right","Can be measured as constitutional right","Can be legally right","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"A professional engineer take the help of COE specifically when he enters into","choices":["Ethical crisis","Doubts","Confusion","Legal complications"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The �risk experts� approach usually","choices":["Utilitarian","Biased","Favourable to employer","None"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"This is not the aim of studying Engineering Ethics","choices":["Addressing un clarity","Analyzing concepts","Engaging sense of responsibility","Procuring faultless results"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineers shall issue public statements only","choices":["On the personal responsibility","Based on the reports sent by higher officers","In objective manner","In subjective manner"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"An engineer may not be held legally liable for causing harm, when the harm is caused","choices":["Internationally","Ignorantly","nNegligently","Recklessly"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the characteristics of Profession is","choices":["It gives scope to exercise one�s skill","It gives monopoly on service","It provides opportunity to help the poor and needy","It demands high standards of honesty"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the views on the responsibility of engineers is","choices":["They are absolutely reliable","They should do good works","They should take reasonable responsibility","They are strictly liable"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the most impediments to responsibility is","choices":["Self deception","Rampant corruption at higher level","Interference by higher officer","Interference by politicians"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"This is not impediment to responsibility","choices":["Self respect","Ignorance","Self deception","Fear"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Conflict of interest exists for an engineer when he is subjected to","choices":["Loyalties","Professional impediments","Professional harassments","Threat"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Professional autonomy means ","choices":["Exercising independent and objective judgements ","Liberty to express independent view","Liberty in selecting the work","Independent body controlling profession"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"It doesn�t amount to misusing the truth","choices":["Biased professional information","Failure to seek out the truth","Withholding information","Deliberation deception"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the ways of misusing the truth is ","choices":["Failure to seek the truth","Exaggerating the truth","Making the confused statement","Making totally false statement"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Good work means","choices":["Work above and beyond the call of duty","Responsible work","Work involving high risk","Superior work done with great care and skill"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Cooking means","choices":["Retaining results which fit the theory","Making deceptive statements","Boiling under pressure","Misleading the public about the quality of product"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Forging means","choices":["Inventing research data which are reported","Mixing material under high pressure","Signing in the name of other person","Strengthening material by special process"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"An example for forging is","choices":["Mentioning of experiments to obtain data which were never conducted","Obtaining data by conducting an experiment","Referring to all research data","Both (a) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Egocentric tendency means","choices":["Interpreting situation from limited view","Superiority complex","Arrogant and irresponsible behaviour","Habit of condemning view of others"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Group thinking","choices":["Is an impediment for responsibility","Leads to confusion and may cause loss","Is an impediment in the progress of work","Is useful to understand different facts of the problem"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Tight couple means","choices":["Binding two beams tightly","Erecting two pillars side by side","Process tightly coupled","Strong adhesive material"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One process or function of one component that affect the other and spread the adverse effect to the entire system is observed in","choices":["Tight coupled","Loosely coupled","Complexly interactive","None"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"In ___________ systems, risk estimation is difficult","choices":["Complexly interactive","Tightly coupled ","Loosely coupled","Both (b) and (C)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"A compound measure of probability and magnitude of adverse effect is known as","choices":["Risk","Benefit","Compensation","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Lying is ","choices":["Intentionally conveying false or misleading information","Deception","Falsehood","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Trimming is ","choices":["Smoothing of irregularities to make the data to appear accurate and precise","Retaining the entire data","Consolidating the data","Both (a) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineering ethics is a ","choices":["Preventive ethics","Developing ethics","Natural ethics","Scientifically developed ethics"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineering ethics ","choices":["Stimulates moral imagination","Provides accurate knowledge in the field of engineering","Stimulates to conduct research","Stresses on time management"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Professional ethics is","choices":["Set of rules related to personal character of professional","Traditional rules observed since a long time","Set of rules passed by professional bodies","Set of standards adopted by professionals"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Professional ethics takes into account of ","choices":["Personnel character of engineers","Temperament of engineers","Religious bent of mind of engineers","Social background of engineers"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineering profession is considered to be like a building its foundation is","choices":["Honesty","Hard and sincere work ","Expert engineering knowledge and skill","Sound common sense and expert knowledge"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the aims in studying engineering ethics is to ","choices":["Gain better in site into the profession","Know the secrets of profession ","Develop analytical skill ","Understand the professional problems"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the aims of engineering ethics is to","choices":["Stimulate the moral imagination","Inspire engineers to acquire in depth knowledge in their field","Acquire new skills in engineering, testing and research","Make engineers self confident in discharging their duties"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"This is not the aim of studying engineering ethics ","choices":["Crimping","Cooking","Forging","Plagiarism"],"correctAnswer":0}]